{
  "id": "d290f1ee-6c54-4b01-90e6-d701748f0884",
  "name": "Valves: Part 2",
  "topicId": "d290f1ee-6c54-4b01-90e6-d701748f0884",
  "questions": [
      {
         "id": "d290f1ee-6c54-4b01-90e6-d701748f0884",
         "topicId": "d290f1ee-6c54-4b01-90e6-d701748f0884",
         "question": "Choose the Valve name:",
         "type": "single_type",
         "options": [
           "Lift Check Valve",
           "Ball Valve",
           "Gate Valve",
           "Angle Globe",
           "Straight Globe Valve",
           "Swing Check"
         ],
         "correctAnswer": ["Straight Globe Valve"],
         "explanation": "",
         "imageNames": ["Figure 13 (A)"]
       },
      {
         "id": "d290f1ee-6c54-4b01-90e6-d701748f0884",
         "topicId": "d290f1ee-6c54-4b01-90e6-d701748f0884",
         "question": "Choose the Valve name:",
         "type": "single_type",
         "options": [
           "Lift Check Valve",
           "Ball Valve",
           "Gate Valve",
           "Angle Globe",
           "Straight Globe Valve",
           "Swing Check"
         ],
         "correctAnswer": ["Swing Check"],
         "explanation": "",
         "imageNames": ["Figure 13 (B)"]
       },
      {
         "id": "d290f1ee-6c54-4b01-90e6-d701748f0884",
         "topicId": "d290f1ee-6c54-4b01-90e6-d701748f0884",
         "question": "Choose the Valve name:",
         "type": "single_type",
         "options": [
           "Lift Check Valve",
           "Ball Valve",
           "Gate Valve",
           "Angle Globe",
           "Straight Globe Valve",
           "Swing Check"
         ],
         "correctAnswer": ["Gate Valve"],
         "explanation": "",
         "imageNames": ["Figure 13 (C)"]
       },
      {
         "id": "d290f1ee-6c54-4b01-90e6-d701748f0884",
         "topicId": "d290f1ee-6c54-4b01-90e6-d701748f0884",
         "question": "Choose the Valve name:",
         "type": "single_type",
         "options": [
           "Lift Check Valve",
           "Ball Valve",
           "Gate Valve",
           "Angle Globe",
           "Straight Globe Valve",
           "Swing Check"
         ],
         "correctAnswer": ["Ball Valve"],
         "explanation": "",
         "imageNames": ["Figure 13 (D)"]
       },
      {
         "id": "d290f1ee-6c54-4b01-90e6-d701748f0884",
         "topicId": "d290f1ee-6c54-4b01-90e6-d701748f0884",
         "question": "Choose the Valve name:",
         "type": "single_type",
         "options": [
           "Lift Check Valve",
           "Ball Valve",
           "Gate Valve",
           "Angle Globe",
           "Straight Globe Valve",
           "Swing Check"
         ],
         "correctAnswer": ["Angle Globe"],
         "explanation": "",
         "imageNames": ["Figure 13 (E)"]
       },
      {
         "id": "d290f1ee-6c54-4b01-90e6-d701748f0884",
         "topicId": "d290f1ee-6c54-4b01-90e6-d701748f0884",
         "question": "Choose the Valve name:",
         "type": "single_type",
         "options": [
           "Lift Check Valve",
           "Ball Valve",
           "Gate Valve",
           "Angle Globe",
           "Straight Globe Valve",
           "Swing Check"
         ],
         "correctAnswer": ["Lift Check Valve"],
         "explanation": "",
         "imageNames": ["Figure 13 (F)"]
       },
        {
          "id": "d290f1ee-6c54-4b01-90e6-d701748f0884",
          "topicId": "d290f1ee-6c54-4b01-90e6-d701748f0884",
          "question": "What is the main advantage of the following valve design features? outside screw and yoke:",
          "type": "single_type",
          "options": [
              "Headroom",
              "Threads do not come in contact with fluids",
              "No packing, less maintenance",
              "Lantern ring: Better lubrication",
              "Easily replaced to accommodate other applications",
              "Pressure loss kept to a minimum",
              "Minute throttling applications",
              "Easy to tell if the valve is open or closed",
              "Very fine throttling at high pressures",
              "Quick response and low maintenance"
          ],
          "correctAnswer": ["Threads do not come in contact with fluids"],
          "explanation": ""
        },
        {
          "id": "d290f1ee-6c54-4b01-90e6-d701748f0884",
          "topicId": "d290f1ee-6c54-4b01-90e6-d701748f0884",
          "question": "What is the main advantage of the following valve design features? non-rising stem:",
          "type": "single_type",
          "options": [
              "Headroom",
              "Threads do not come in contact with fluids",
              "No packing, less maintenance",
              "Lantern ring: Better lubrication",
              "Easily replaced to accommodate other applications",
              "Pressure loss kept to a minimum",
              "Minute throttling applications",
              "Easy to tell if the valve is open or closed",
              "Very fine throttling at high pressures",
              "Quick response and low maintenance"
          ],
          "correctAnswer": ["Headroom"],
          "explanation": ""
        },
        {
          "id": "d290f1ee-6c54-4b01-90e6-d701748f0884",
          "topicId": "d290f1ee-6c54-4b01-90e6-d701748f0884",
          "question": "What is the main advantage of the following valve design features? diaphragm valve:",
          "type": "single_type",
          "options": [
              "Headroom",
              "Threads do not come in contact with fluids",
              "No packing, less maintenance",
              "Lantern ring: Better lubrication",
              "Easily replaced to accommodate other applications",
              "Pressure loss kept to a minimum",
              "Minute throttling applications",
              "Easy to tell if the valve is open or closed",
              "Very fine throttling at high pressures",
              "Quick response and low maintenance"
          ],
          "correctAnswer": ["No packing, less maintenance"],
          "explanation": ""
        },
        {
          "id": "d290f1ee-6c54-4b01-90e6-d701748f0884",
          "topicId": "d290f1ee-6c54-4b01-90e6-d701748f0884",
          "question": "What is the main advantage of the following valve design features? lantern ring:",
          "type": "single_type",
          "options": [
              "Headroom",
              "Threads do not come in contact with fluids",
              "No packing, less maintenance",
              "Lantern ring: Better lubrication",
              "Easily replaced to accommodate other applications",
              "Pressure loss kept to a minimum",
              "Minute throttling applications",
              "Easy to tell if the valve is open or closed",
              "Very fine throttling at high pressures",
              "Quick response and low maintenance"
          ],
          "correctAnswer": ["Better lubrication"],
          "explanation": ""
        },
        {
          "id": "d290f1ee-6c54-4b01-90e6-d701748f0884",
          "topicId": "d290f1ee-6c54-4b01-90e6-d701748f0884",
          "question": "What is the main advantage of the following valve design features? composition discs:",
          "type": "single_type",
          "options": [
              "Headroom",
              "Threads do not come in contact with fluids",
              "No packing, less maintenance",
              "Lantern ring: Better lubrication",
              "Easily replaced to accommodate other applications",
              "Pressure loss kept to a minimum",
              "Minute throttling applications",
              "Easy to tell if the valve is open or closed",
              "Very fine throttling at high pressures",
              "Quick response and low maintenance"
          ],
          "correctAnswer": ["Easily replaced to accommodate other applications"],
          "explanation": ""
        },
        {
          "id": "d290f1ee-6c54-4b01-90e6-d701748f0884",
          "topicId": "d290f1ee-6c54-4b01-90e6-d701748f0884",
          "question": "What is the main advantage of the following valve design features? Y pattern valves:",
          "type": "single_type",
          "options": [
              "Headroom",
              "Threads do not come in contact with fluids",
              "No packing, less maintenance",
              "Lantern ring: Better lubrication",
              "Easily replaced to accommodate other applications",
              "Pressure loss kept to a minimum",
              "Minute throttling applications",
              "Easy to tell if the valve is open or closed",
              "Very fine throttling at high pressures",
              "Quick response and low maintenance"
          ],
          "correctAnswer": ["Pressure loss kept to a minimum"],
          "explanation": ""
        },
        {
          "id": "d290f1ee-6c54-4b01-90e6-d701748f0884",
          "topicId": "d290f1ee-6c54-4b01-90e6-d701748f0884",
          "question": "What is the main advantage of the following valve design features? plug disc valves:",
          "type": "single_type",
          "options": [
              "Headroom",
              "Threads do not come in contact with fluids",
              "No packing, less maintenance",
              "Lantern ring: Better lubrication",
              "Easily replaced to accommodate other applications",
              "Pressure loss kept to a minimum",
              "Minute throttling applications",
              "Easy to tell if the valve is open or closed",
              "Very fine throttling at high pressures",
              "Quick response and low maintenance"
          ],
          "correctAnswer": ["Minute throttling applications"],
          "explanation": ""
        },
        {
          "id": "d290f1ee-6c54-4b01-90e6-d701748f0884",
          "topicId": "d290f1ee-6c54-4b01-90e6-d701748f0884",
          "question": "What is the main advantage of the following valve design features? rising stem valves:",
          "type": "single_type",
          "options": [
              "Headroom",
              "Threads do not come in contact with fluids",
              "No packing, less maintenance",
              "Lantern ring: Better lubrication",
              "Easily replaced to accommodate other applications",
              "Pressure loss kept to a minimum",
              "Minute throttling applications",
              "Easy to tell if the valve is open or closed",
              "Very fine throttling at high pressures",
              "Quick response and low maintenance"
          ],
          "correctAnswer": ["Easy to tell if the valve is open or closed"],
          "explanation": ""
        },
        {
          "id": "d290f1ee-6c54-4b01-90e6-d701748f0884",
          "topicId": "d290f1ee-6c54-4b01-90e6-d701748f0884",
          "question": "What is the main advantage of the following valve design features? needle valves:",
          "type": "single_type",
          "options": [
              "Headroom",
              "Threads do not come in contact with fluids",
              "No packing, less maintenance",
              "Lantern ring: Better lubrication",
              "Easily replaced to accommodate other applications",
              "Pressure loss kept to a minimum",
              "Minute throttling applications",
              "Easy to tell if the valve is open or closed",
              "Very fine throttling at high pressures",
              "Quick response and low maintenance"
          ],
          "correctAnswer": ["Very fine throttling at high pressures"],
          "explanation": ""
        },
        {
          "id": "d290f1ee-6c54-4b01-90e6-d701748f0884",
          "topicId": "d290f1ee-6c54-4b01-90e6-d701748f0884",
          "question": "What is the main advantage of the following valve design features? ball valves:",
          "type": "single_type",
          "options": [
              "Headroom",
              "Threads do not come in contact with fluids",
              "No packing, less maintenance",
              "Lantern ring: Better lubrication",
              "Easily replaced to accommodate other applications",
              "Pressure loss kept to a minimum",
              "Minute throttling applications",
              "Easy to tell if the valve is open or closed",
              "Very fine throttling at high pressures",
              "Quick response and low maintenance"
          ],
          "correctAnswer": ["Quick response and low maintenance"],
          "explanation": ""
        },
        {
          "id": "d290f1ee-6c54-4b01-90e6-d701748f0884",
          "topicId": "d290f1ee-6c54-4b01-90e6-d701748f0884",
          "question": "What are valves that require only a 90º turn from full open to full closed classified as?",
          "type": "single_type",
          "options": [
            "¼ turn.",
            "Quick opening.",
            "Rotating stem.",
            "Sliding stem."
          ],
          "correctAnswer": ["¼ turn."],
          "explanation": ""
        },
        {
          "id": "d290f1ee-6c54-4b01-90e6-d701748f0884",
          "topicId": "d290f1ee-6c54-4b01-90e6-d701748f0884",
          "question": "What is the S or SWP rating on a valve related to?",
          "type": "single_type",
          "options": [
            "Slurries or sour waste products.",
            "Maximum pressure allowed at saturation steam temperature.",
            "Safe or safe working pressure.",
            "The speed of response to open or close the valve."
          ],
          "correctAnswer": ["Maximum pressure allowed at saturation steam temperature."],
          "explanation": ""
        },
        {
          "id": "d290f1ee-6c54-4b01-90e6-d701748f0884",
          "topicId": "d290f1ee-6c54-4b01-90e6-d701748f0884",
          "question": "What physical damage is most likely to occur to the plug or seat of a non-lubricated metal-to-metal plug valve used under high pressure?",
          "type": "single_type",
          "options": [
            "Galling.",
            "Scoring.",
            "Seat warp.",
            "Wire drawing."
          ],
          "correctAnswer": ["Galling."],
          "explanation": ""
        },
        {
          "id": "d290f1ee-6c54-4b01-90e6-d701748f0884",
          "topicId": "d290f1ee-6c54-4b01-90e6-d701748f0884",
          "question": "What condition in a system would most likely require the use of a tilting disc check valve?",
          "type": "single_type",
          "options": [
            "Turbulent flow.",
            "Low-velocity flow.",
            "High-velocity flow.",
            "Presence of particulate matter in the fluid."
          ],
          "correctAnswer": ["Low-velocity flow."],
          "explanation": ""
        },
        {
          "id": "d290f1ee-6c54-4b01-90e6-d701748f0884",
          "topicId": "d290f1ee-6c54-4b01-90e6-d701748f0884",
          "question": "An OS&Y valve refers to ______________________________.",
          "type": "single_type",
          "options": [
              "an outside screw and yoke.",
              "an open stem and yoke.",
              "an outside stem and yoke.",
              "an open screw and yoke.",
              "an operating screw and yoke."
          ],
          "correctAnswer": ["an outside screw and yoke."],
          "explanation": ""
        },
        {
          "id": "d290f1ee-6c54-4b01-90e6-d701748f0884",
          "topicId": "d290f1ee-6c54-4b01-90e6-d701748f0884",
          "question": "List two (2) major advantages of the OS&Y valve.",
          "type": "checkbox_type",
          "options": [
            "The valve stem threads do not come in contact with the fluid.",
            "It is easier to maintain and lubricate."
          ],
          "correctAnswer": [
            "The valve stem threads do not come in contact with the fluid.",
            "It is easier to maintain and lubricate."
          ],
          "explanation": ""
        },
        {
          "id": "d290f1ee-6c54-4b01-90e6-d701748f0884",
          "topicId": "d290f1ee-6c54-4b01-90e6-d701748f0884",
          "question": "State the purpose of the following. Stuffing box:",
          "type": "single_type",
          "options": [
              "To hold the packing which prevents fluid leakage.",
              "To hold the packing gland and packing.",
              "To compress the packing.",
              "To lubricate the valve stem."
          ],
          "correctAnswer": ["To hold the packing which prevents fluid leakage."],
          "explanation": ""
        },
        {
          "id": "d290f1ee-6c54-4b01-90e6-d701748f0884",
          "topicId": "d290f1ee-6c54-4b01-90e6-d701748f0884",
          "question": "State the purpose of the following. Packing nut:",
          "type": "single_type",
          "options": [
              "To hold the packing which prevents fluid leakage.",
              "To hold the packing gland and packing.",
              "To compress the packing.",
              "To lubricate the valve stem."
          ],
          "correctAnswer": ["To hold the packing gland and packing."],
          "explanation": ""
        },
        {
          "id": "d290f1ee-6c54-4b01-90e6-d701748f0884",
          "topicId": "d290f1ee-6c54-4b01-90e6-d701748f0884",
          "question": "State the purpose of the following. Packing gland:",
          "type": "single_type",
          "options": [
              "To hold the packing which prevents fluid leakage.",
              "To hold the packing gland and packing.",
              "To compress the packing.",
              "To lubricate the valve stem."
          ],
          "correctAnswer": ["To compress the packing."],
          "explanation": ""
        },
        {
          "id": "d290f1ee-6c54-4b01-90e6-d701748f0884",
          "topicId": "d290f1ee-6c54-4b01-90e6-d701748f0884",
          "question": "State the purpose of the following. Lantern ring:",
          "type": "single_type",
          "options": [
            "To hold the packing which prevents fluid leakage.",
            "To hold the packing gland and packing.",
            "To compress the packing.",
            "To lubricate the valve stem."
          ],
          "correctAnswer": ["To lubricate the valve stem."],
          "explanation": ""
        },
        {
          "id": "d290f1ee-6c54-4b01-90e6-d701748f0884",
          "topicId": "d290f1ee-6c54-4b01-90e6-d701748f0884",
          "question": "What special feature might be required for a gate valve installed in a vertical line?",
          "type": "single_type",
          "options": [
            "Built-in bypass valve to equalize pressure across the disc.",
            "Bonnet bleed valve to prevent pressure lock.",
            "Drain valve tapping above the disc.",
            "Small bleed hole in one of the discs to prevent pressure lock."
          ],
          "correctAnswer": ["Drain valve tapping above the disc."],
          "explanation": ""
        },
        {
          "id": "d290f1ee-6c54-4b01-90e6-d701748f0884",
          "topicId": "d290f1ee-6c54-4b01-90e6-d701748f0884",
          "question": "What flow condition can be reduced or eliminated with the use of a spring-loaded check valve?",
          "type": "single_type",
          "options": [
            "Disc chatter.",
            "Water hammer.",
            "Velocity erosion.",
            "Turbulence."
          ],
          "correctAnswer": ["Water hammer."],
          "explanation": ""
        },
        {
          "id": "d290f1ee-6c54-4b01-90e6-d701748f0884",
          "topicId": "d290f1ee-6c54-4b01-90e6-d701748f0884",
          "question": "What is required in most plants before any component can be removed from a system or piece of equipment?",
          "type": "single_type",
          "options": [
            "Work order.",
            "Engineering approval.",
            "Safe work permit.",
            "Safety meeting."
          ],
          "correctAnswer": ["Safe work permit."],
          "explanation": ""
        },
        {
          "id": "d290f1ee-6c54-4b01-90e6-d701748f0884",
          "topicId": "d290f1ee-6c54-4b01-90e6-d701748f0884",
          "question": "What is the correct packing size to use if the valve stem measures 25 mm (1'') OD and the stuffing box measures 44 mm (1-3/4'')?",
          "type": "single_type",
          "options": [
            "4.75 mm (3/16'').",
            "9.5 mm (3/8'').",
            "19 mm (3/4'').",
            "69 mm (2-3/4'')."
          ],
          "correctAnswer": ["9.5 mm (3/8'')."],
          "explanation": ""
        },
        {
          "id": "d290f1ee-6c54-4b01-90e6-d701748f0884",
          "topicId": "d290f1ee-6c54-4b01-90e6-d701748f0884",
          "question": "Which group is still considered to be at the forefront in setting valve standards?",
          "type": "single_type",
          "options": [
            "ASTM.",
            "ANSI/ASME.",
            "CSA.",
            "MSS."
          ],
          "correctAnswer": ["MSS."],
          "explanation": ""
        },
        {
          "id": "d290f1ee-6c54-4b01-90e6-d701748f0884",
          "topicId": "d290f1ee-6c54-4b01-90e6-d701748f0884",
          "question": "Why would a piping system built to B31.3 standards require a valve built to the API 6D valve standard?",
          "type": "single_type",
          "options": [
            "There is a petroleum fluid in the line.",
            "The valve has to be trimmed to fire protection standards.",
            "The valve stem must be isolated in such a manner that there is no possibility of leakage around the valve stem.",
            "A bubble-tight seal is required between the disc and seats."
          ],
          "correctAnswer": ["A bubble-tight seal is required between the disc and seats."],
          "explanation": ""
        }
  ]
}
